A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Business Manager, Henry James Subject Files, Series 1 FA811
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Business Manager, Henry James Subject Files, Series 1
1912-1919
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
FA811
0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
1 box.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 210-1
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Other Finding Aids
FA808 Rockefeller University records, Business Manager, Correspondence, Series 2.
FA137 Rockefeller University records, Business Manager, Subject Files, Series 3.
FA809 Rockefeller University records, Business Manager, Annual Reports, Series 4.
FA810 Rockefeller University records, Business Manager, Budget Histories, Series 7.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
Consists of subject files.
Operations management; Biology -- Research; Biochemistry; Medicine, Preventive; Life sciences; Medical technology; Hospitals; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Vivisection; Prevention and health; Medical research
- Business Manager - Henry James, 1912-1919; 1 box (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists primarily of correspondence arranged by subject.
  Arrangement note
  Arranged in alphabetical/chronological order.
  - Equipment, 1912
    - Merritt & Co. (lockers)
    - Geo. H. Wahman Mfg. (Metabolism cages)
  - Grants
    - Frederick S. Lee, 1912-1913
    - J.U. Nef, 1913
    - G.H. Nuttall, 1913-1914
    - Rickard Weil, 1913
    - C.A. Yllner, 1914
  - Kendrick, Murdock, 1914
    Deals with payment for trial transcript of vivisection trial involving University of Pennsylvania (Commonwealth vs Sweet)
  - Knoop, Franz, 1912-1913
    Deals with U.S. Lectures and offer of RIMR Membership
  - Lenox hill Settlement, 1915-1918
  - Mulford, H.K. Company, 1913-1917
  - Norris, James U., 1913-1914
  - Patterson, William, 1915-1917
    During period as farm superintendent at Princeton
  - Personnel, 1913
    - Grace, Leonard F.
    - Zacharias, G.
    - Zanotti, Pirro
  - Staggers, 1915-1918
    Deals with F.S. Jones expedition to Patagonia
  - U.S. Armed Services, 1917-1918
    - RIMR policies regarding Institute men in service. Lit of Institute men in service
  - Waterproofing Co., 1913-1914
  - Weeks, Lester, 1913
    - Correspondence regarding employment of Stone & Webster man as assistant for H. James
  - Westminster Club, 1916
    - H. James address in Buffalo on Institute work and newspaper reports
  - White Company, 1916-1917
    - Car for Princeton
  - Wins low, C.E.A., 1915
    - Assorted items 2 letters typescript signed
  - Various (assorted subjects)
    - Course for laboratory technicians, 1918
    - Eggs supply of fertile eggs for Dr. Ebeling Mitchell, Nahum 1916 employment at Princeton, 1912-1915
    - Monahan's express truck damage to fence, 1919
    - Parke-Davis. Preparation and sale of Luetin, 1914-1916
    - Salvarsan. Deaths from 606, 1910-1912
  - Zincograph Company, 1917-1919
    Duplication of reports